

Vili Tajnic

Nationality: Slovenian

(+386) 051322553

Date of birth: 02/08/1970

Gender: Male

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vilit/

Skype: live:vili.tajnic

○ Whatsapp Messenger: +38651322553

Viber: +38651322553

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vilit/

Github: : https://github.com/ViliTajnic

Address: Novo Polje c. XIV 29, 1260 Ljubljana (Slovenia)

ABOUT ME

I can best describe myself as a problem solver, which happens to land in the IT department in the mid-nineties. IT technology and rise of the dot-coms made such an impact on me that I am still here, busy with new IT concepts and new computer technologies. The only difference is that, now I carefully choose what to follow and keep in focus, because it simply became unmanageable to follow everything like we did back in the days. Currently I'm engaged in certification study for AWS Certified Solution Architect – Professional. I've became very passionate about the cloud technologies around 10 years ago when I first got engaged with Google Apps and their cloud services. At that time I realised that these technologies are literally going to change the world and the way we interact/develop/consume IT resources.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance IT Administration and Support (cca. 100 users)

ŠENT - NGO [05/04/2001 – Current]

Address: Ljubljana City: Ljubljana

- Mail server and applications support on Google Apps
- AWS S3/EC2/AppSync and other migration tools
- Python/Django programming
- Security and Firewall administration (on-prem)
- Windows environment implementation and support (Hybrid Cloud)
- Unstructured data cloud implementation and support (On-prem Cloud Solution and Google Drive)
- o User profile support

Solutions Sales Engineer

Printec S.I. d.o.o. [06/02/2020 - 01/07/2020]

Address: Ljubljana (Slovenia)

- Analyse potential markets
- Sales Team technical assist
- o Products and technology knowledge support
- o Strategic thinking management perspective assist

Value Add Reseller Team Lead

ASBIS d.o.o. [15/05/2018 – 07/10/2019]

Address: Trzin (Slovenia)

- o Distribution sales opportunities identification and business needs development
- o Distribution channel development (SonicWall, Supermicro, Inifindat, and other vendors)
- o General sales promotions, marketing activities and events organisations
- o Partner education security learning sessions
- Project sales pipeline development

Regional Account Manager (SI, HR, BiH, RS)

Hitachi Data Systems (Vantara) [01/03/2016 - 31/08/2017]

Address: Vienna (Austria)

- Sales opportunities identification and business development
- Sales projects development
- o General sales promotions, marketing activities and events coordination/organisations
- Customers education and related sales activities
- Sales forecasting and reporting

Channel Manager Adriatic and South East Area

Hitachi Data Systems (Vantara) [01/05/2012 - 01/03/2016]

Address: Vienna (Austria)

- New partners and partner's business plans development and enforcement
- o Business planning process lead with partner's key decision makers at the management and sales level
- Development of the various marketing activities
- Partner recruiting and initiation process leader
- Hitachi technology educations for partners
- o Partner sales activities
- Sales forecasting and reporting for the channel Adriatic (SI, HR, BiH, RS, MK, MT, AL, KS, CY) and South East Area (HU, BG, GR)

Storage sales engineer - consultant

S&T Slovenija d.d. [01/01/2012 – 30/04/2012]

Address: Ljubljana

- Storage sales campaigns
- Marketing activates and vendors management (EMC, HDS, HP, IBM)
- Strategic accounts development
- Sales forecasting and reporting

Head of department Storage systems

S&T Slovenija d.d. [01/12/2007 – 31/12/2011]

Address: Ljubljana

- Storage and SAN tech Team Lead management (10 engineers)
- Technical project management (complex solutions)
- Data center architecture designs and resources planning (major activity)
- o Pre-sales and customer solutions development

Systems and Storage systems engineer

S&T Slovenija d.d. [01/05/2003 – 01/12/2007]

Address: Ljubljana

- o Technical project management and occasional team coordination
- Hands-on enterprise and mid-range storage hardware and software (major activity)
- o Planning and architecture design of different on-premise datacenter solutions
- o Pre-sales and technical customer support
- Technical support of enterprise customers compute and storage on-premise setups (eg. NLB, Telekom SI, Krka, ...)

Systems engineer and project manager

Triglif d.o.o. (*Tehnološki Park Ljubljana*) [01/02/1999 – 30/04/2003]

Address: Ljubljana

- Team lead of Microsoft trained professionals (up to 5 employees)
- o Infrastructure solutions architecture and planning
- o Pre-sales and customer consulting
- Support for Microsoft based solutions (AD, Exchange, MSCS,...)

Technical team lead and RF engineer

S.T.I. Telecom d.o.o. (acquired by Telemach d.d. in 1998) [01/05/1996 – 01/02/1999]

Address: Ljubljana

- Development of new content/services for cable network operator
- Management and support of the RF infrastructure
- o Management and support of the RF Head End-receiving station
- Maintenance of the RF cable network and customer's support

Electronic assembly / Technical support

IMP Trata d.d. (acquired by Danfoss) [01/09/1989 - 15/05/1992]

Address: Ljubljana

- Electronic air-condition controls assembly production
- Factory production maintenance of Computer Numerical Control machinery

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science

The Open University [01/09/2003 – 28/12/2011]

Address: Milton Keynes (United Kingdom)

Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Courses:

T171 You, Your Computer and the Net

M206 Computing: An Object-Oriented Approach

MT262 Putting Computer Systems to Work

T224 Computers and processors

T306 Managing complexity: a systems approach

T214 Understanding systems: making sense of complexity

T324 Keeping ahead in information and communication technologies

Electrician-Electronics

Electronics High School Ljubljana - Šentvid [01/09/1985 - 25/06/1989]

Address: Ljubljana

Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Design, measurement, construction, repair and maintenance in the fields of automation, industrial electronics, RTV electronics, telephony, computer equipment

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

Slovenian

English

LISTENING: C2 READING: C2 WRITING: C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION: C2
SPOKEN INTERACTION: C2

Serbian

LISTENING: C2 READING: C2 WRITING: B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION: C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION: C2 Croatian

LISTENING: C2 READING: C2 WRITING: C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION: C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION: C2

German

LISTENING: B1 READING: B1 WRITING: A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION: A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION: A2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Cloud Computing / Cloud / AWS / Google Cloud / EMCDell / Hitachi Data Systems / Storage / Storage Area Network / Enterprise Storage / IT Infrastructure / Partner Management / Channel Management / Microsoft Technologies / Scripting in Python andor Bash / Python / Linux / System Administration / PERL (elementary proficiency for parsing) / C++ / Python Flask / Python (Django) / GIT (GitHub)

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: AM
Driving Licence: A1
Driving Licence: A2
Driving Licence: A
Driving Licence: B

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organisational skills

- leadership (I was responsible for number of teams of 5-10 people)
- good organisational skills gained as technical project manager responsible for complex solutions integration and development

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication and interpersonal skills

- good communication skills gained trough my entire career at first as a support engineer and latter as a sales account manager
- excellent presentation skills gained through my experience as a pre-sales and channel manager

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

Certificates:

- Python programming Jul. 2020
- o AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate Aug. 2020
- o AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Jul. 2020
- o SonicWALL Sales Professional Sep. 2018
- MCSE (Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer) NT/2000 May 2000
- o Checkpoint Firewall Administrator March 2003
- o CSA HP-UX (Certified Systems Administrator HP-UX) Dec. 2004
- o EMC Proven Professional Jan. 2005
- o HDS 9900/9900V/USP series course Oct. 2005
- HDS 9500/AMS/WMS series course Jan. 2005
- Certified McDATA SAN Professional (CMSP) Sep. 2006
- o Brocade Certified Fabric Professional Sep. 2007
- EMC Proven Professional EMCCE CLARiiON Jul. 2007
- o EMC Proven Professional EMCCE Symmetrix Sep. 2007
- EMC Proven Professional EMCCIE Storage Management Specialist Jul. 2007